Guide to the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Manuscript Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- File List, Series I
  - "S"
    - Shenstone, William, 1714-1763
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Halesowen, Worcs., 1758 Jun 27 (Box 12, Folder 540)
        Mutilated with severe loss of text Tinker 1908
      - 15 ANS and ALS to John Scott Hylton, [Halesowen, Worcs.], 1755-60 (Box 12, Folder 541)
        Tinker 1910
    - Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1751-1816
      See also: Box 12, folder 545
      - Autograph manuscript fragment of an unidentified play, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 542)
        Mutilated with severe loss of text. Accompanied by John J. Brown's "A Fragment of a Lost Play by R. B. Sheridan," typescript, corrected and signed. Accompanied by clippings regarding Sheridan. Tinker 1912
    - Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1809 or 10-1888
      - ALS to William Ross, Frampton, 1838 Oct 13 (Box 12, Folder 543)
        Tinker 1916
      - ALS to Robert J. Watts, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 544)
        Probably accompanying the gift of a few pages of manuscript of the elder Sheridan. Tinker 1912
    - Sheridan, Thomas, 1719-1788
      See: Box 5, folder 151
      - See: Box 12, folder 545
    - Simson and Bergman
      - Manuscript itemized bill to [Richard Brinsley] Sheridan, 1776 (Box 12, Folder 545)
        Bill from tailor Tinker 1913
    - Skeffington, Lumley St. George, Sir, 1771-1850
      - ALS to [Hester Lynch Piozzi], Skeffington Hall, Leicestershire, 1808 Jun 30 (Box 12, Folder 546)
        Tinker 1918
    - Smith, James
      - Manuscript itemized bill to [Thomas Sheridan], 1762-63 (Box 12, Folder 547)
    - Southey, Robert, 1774-1843
      - AMS (draft) of Madoc, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 548-549)
        Bound in two volumes Tinker 1938
      - ALS to Joseph Cottle, Exeter, 1799 Sep 22 (Box 13, Folder 550)
        Tinker 1940
      - ALS to George Dyer, Keswick, 1827 Jul 21 (Box 13, Folder 551)
        Tinker 1941
      - ALS to John May, Burton, Hants, 1797 Jul 11 (Box 13, Folder 552)
        Tinker 1942
      - ALS to John May, Burton, 1797 Aug 15 (Box 13, Folder 553)
        Tinker 1943
      - ALS to John May, Ottery and Exeter, 1799 Sep 3 (Box 13, Folder 554)
        Tinker 1944
      - ALS to John May, Lisbon, 1801 Mar 27 (Box 13, Folder 555)
        Tinker 1945
      - ALS to John James Morgan, Keswick, 1811 Nov 13 (Box 13, Folder 556)
        Tinker 1946
      - ALS to William Taylor, Westbury, [1798] Jul 24 (Box 13, Folder 557)
        Tinker 1947
      - ALS (photostat) to Samuel Taylor Coleridge, 1807 Dec 9 (Box 13, Folder 558)
        Owner of original unknown
    - Streatfeild, Sophia, 1754-1835
      - ALS to Mrs. Thrale [later, Hester Lynch Piozzi], London, [1778 May 7] (Box 13, Folder 559)
        Signed with initials Tinker 1999
    - Swinburne, Algernon Charles, 1837-1909
      - "A Ballad of Life," autograph manuscript poem, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 560)
        In 8 stanzas. Paper watermarked 1863 Tinker 2003
      - "A Death on Easter Day," autograph manuscript sonnet, 1882 Apr (Box 13, Folder 561)
        On the death of Dante Gabriel Rossetti Tinker 2005
      - "In the Orchard," autograph manuscript poem, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 562)
        In 10 stanzas Tinker 2004
      - [It was a' for our rightful king...], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 563)
        Manuscript copy in Swinburne's hand of the four stanzas of Robert Burns's poem. Autograph note at end: "Copied from memory by Alg. Ch. Swinburne for Philip Marston." Tinker 2006
      - ALS to Matthew Arnold, London, 1882 Jul 19 (Box 14, Folder 564)
        Tinker 2007
      - Proof sheets of The Heptalogia, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 565)
        Tinker 2025
    - Swinnerton, Frank, 1884-1982
      - ALS to C. E. Andrews, New York City, 1923 Dec 22 (Box 14, Folder 566)
        With envelope
  - "T"
    - Temple, Anne
      - 2 ALS to William Johnston Temple, Mamhead, 1770 (Box 14, Folder 567)
    - Temple, William Johnston, 1739-1796
      See also: Box 6, folder 209
      - See also: Box 11, folder 467 See also: Box 14, folder 567
      - 4 ALS to Anne Temple, 1783 (Box 14, Folder 568)
        To his wife
      - Notebook, holograph, 1795-96 (Box 14, Folder 569)
        Tinker 2040
    - Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892
      - AMS of three poems with two others transcribed by John Hearth (?), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 570)
        Tinker 2041
      - AMS of text from The princess (Canto IV, lines 353-390), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 571)
        Tinker 2042
      - AMS of "Sea dreams", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 572)
        Tinker 2043
      - AMS of "XXXIX 'In Memoriam'", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 573)
        Tinker 2044
      - AMS of note to appear at heading of the poem, "Despair", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 574)
        Tinker 2045
      - ALS to Henry Gardiner Adams, Boxley, 1843 May 1 (Box 14, Folder 575)
        Tinker 2046
      - ANS to [Sir Alexander Grant?], n.p. (Box 14, Folder 576)
        Tinker 2047
      - ALS to James Thomas Knowles, Farringford, Isle of Wight, 1874 Jan 2 (Box 14, Folder 577)
        Tinker 2048
      - ANS to James Thomas Knowles, Farringford, Isle of Wight, n.y. Dec 18 (Box 14, Folder 578)
        Tinker 2049
      - ANS to [George] Macdonald, Farringford, Isle of Wight, 1866 May 15 (Box 14, Folder 579)
        Tinker 2050
      - ALS to Henry Cholmondeley Pennell, Farringford, Isle of Wight, [1874] (Box 14, Folder 580)
        Tinker 2051
      - LS (in Hallam Tennyson's hand) to May Probyn, n.p., 1881 Aug (Box 14, Folder 581)
        Tinker 2052
      - ALS to Sir John Simeon, Farringford, Isle of Wight, [1856 Feb-Mar] (Box 14, Folder 582)
        Tinker 2053
      - ALS to William Makepeace Thackeray, n.p., 1859 Dec 28 (Box 14, Folder 583)
        Tinker 2054
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, n.p., [1851] Mar 7 (Box 14, Folder 584)
        Tinker 2055
      - ANS to an unknown correspondenct, n.p., [ca. 1854?] (Box 14, Folder 585)
        Tinker 2056
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, Farringford, Isle of Wight, [1882 Oct?] (Box 14, Folder 586)
        Tinker 2057
    - Tennyson, Emily Sellwood Tennyson, Baroness, 1813-1896
      - AMS, 9 lines. A scrap., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 587)
        Analysis of the contents of three sections of In Memoriam Tinker 2108
    - Thomson, Elizabeth (Burns)
      - ALS to Mr. Simpson, Shawlands, Scotland, 1863 Dec 29 (Box 14, Folder 588)
        Thomson was a daughter of Robert Burns. Tinker 464
    - Thomson, James, 1700-1748
      - ALS to "Dear Sir", 1730 Jun 30 (Box 14, Folder 589)
        Letter presenting recipient with a copy of The Seasons. Annotated in pencil: "To Barretti the Author of the Dictionary." Accompanied by: TLS from Alan D. McKillop to CBT, 1953 Oct 8, identifying the recipient as Paolo Rolli.
    - Thomson, James, 1834-1882
      - ALS to the Rev. Mr. Frederick Langbridge, Kirby Muxloe, 1882 Mar 4 (Box 14, Folder 590)
        Tinker 2135
    - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882
      - "The Duke's Children," autograph manuscript, n.d.
        3 volumes. Bound at the end of volume 3 is a letter from Henry M. Trollope (1918 Feb 11) presenting the manuscript to a British Red Cross sale. Bookplates of A. Edward Newton and Chauncey Brewster Tinker. Tinker 2157
        See: Oversize, VOL, folder 643
      - "Phineas Finn. Saint Paul's Magazine October 1867 to May 1869," autograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 591-599)
        Tinker 2155
      - "Phineas Redux. Graphic - 1873," autograph manuscript, n.d.
        One volume. Inscribed: "Given to Harry Trollope by the author, November 1873." Bookplates of Henry M. Trollope and Chauncey Brewster Tinker. Tinker 2156
        See: Oversize, VOL, folder 644
      - ANS to [James T. Fields?], New York, 1862 Mar 12 (Box 15, Folder 600)
        Tinker 2158
      - ALS to Mr. M. FitzGerald, London, 1879 Jul 1 (Box 15, Folder 601)
        Accompanied by Fitzgerald's letter, Bailieborough, Ireland, 30 Jun 1879 Tinker 2159
      - ALS to Alexander Ireland, London, 1878 Nov 29 (Box 15, Folder 602)
        Tinker 2160
      - ALS to Mr. MacKerke [?], Yarmouth, 1863 Apr 19 (Box 15, Folder 603)
        Tinker 2161
      - AN (third person) to Smith and Elder, Waltham Cross, 1862 Aug 13 (Box 15, Folder 604)
        Tinker 2162
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, Switzerland, 1878 Aug 15 (Box 15, Folder 605)
        Tinker 2163
      - Broadside entitled "Vanity Fair. April 5, 1873. Men of the Day, No. 60. 'A Novelist.'", 1873 Apr 5 (Box 15, Folder 606)
    - Trumbull, J. Hammond (James Hammond), 1821-1897
      - ALS to Henry M. Dexter, Hartford, 1866 Jan 25 (Box 15, Folder 607)
        Concerning John A. Albro's Life of Thomas Shepard and the Synod of 1646
  - "V"
    - Vane, William Holles Vane, Viscount, 1714-1789
      - Printed advertisement distributed when Frances Anne, Viscountess Vane, eloped from her husband, [ca. 1737] (Box 15, Folder 608)
        Accompanied by a manuscript note of explanation in an unidentified hand Tinker 1936
    - Vesey, Elizabeth Vesey, 1715?-1791
      - ALS to [George Townshend?], n.p., 1772 Sep (Box 15, Folder 609)
        Tinker 2261
    - Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901
      - ALS to Adelaide, Dowager Queen of Great Britain, Windsor Castle, 1849 Nov 9 (Box 15, Folder 610)
        Tinker 2262
  - "W"
    - Warton, Joseph, 1722-1800
      - ALS to [Elizabeth Robinson Montagu], Winton, 1779 Nov 11 (Box 15, Folder 611)
        Tinker 2282
    - Watts, Isaac, 1674-1748
      - ALS to the Rev. Dr. Philip Doddridge, Newington, 1741 Apr 11 (Box 15, Folder 612)
        Tinker 2285
      - ALS to [William] Duncombe, Newington, 1734 Nov 1 (Box 15, Folder 613)
        At head of letter: "Letter LXXXI. The Rev. Dr. Watts to Mr. Duncombe." Tinker 2286
      - ALS to Elisha Williams, Newington near London, 1738 Jun 7 (Box 15, Folder 614)
        Accompanied by clipping from an unidentified Boston newspaper (possibly Transcript ) giving text of the letter. Tinker 2287
    - Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900
      - AMS of "The Fisherman and His Soul" (Box 16, Folder 615)
        p. 30 only Tinker 2296
      - ALS to [Marie Anne] de Bovet, London, [ca. 1890] (Box 16, Folder 616)
        Thanks her for an article and praises her translations of his writings. Tinker 2297
    - Wilkes, John, 1727-1797
      - ALS to William Fitzherbert, Modena, Italy, 1765 Jan 17 (Box 16, Folder 617)
        Tinker 2306
      - ALS to George Johnstone, Prince's Court, London, 1786 Dec 24 (Box 16, Folder 618)
        Tinker 2307
      - ALS to George Johnstone, Prince's Court, London, 1787 Apr 11 (Box 16, Folder 619)
        Tinker 2308
      - ALS to George Johnstone, Prince's Court, London, 1787 Apr 21 (Box 16, Folder 620)
        Accompanied by an engraved portrait of Wilkes Tinker 2309
      - AL to [Jean Baptiste Antoine Suard], London, [1768] Aug 5 (Box 16, Folder 621)
        Tinker 2310
    - Wollstonecraft, Mary, 1759-1797
      - ALS "M. Imlay" to "Mr. J. Thomson", [Havre], [1795] Apr 9 (Box 16, Folder 622)
        With 2 portraits of Wollstonecraft Tinker 2313
    - Wordsworth, Dorothy, 1771-1855
      - AMS of "A Sketch -- Unfinished", 1831 Aug 13 (Box 16, Folder 623)
        Tinker 2315
    - Wordsworth, William, 1770-1850
      - AMS poem, 5 lines signed, 1842 Mar 4 (Box 16, Folder 624)
        Includes note, "Addressed to 'Anna Ricketts from her affectionate friend William Wordsworth'. This is the final part of Sonnet #37..."
      - AMS of "Written at Cora Linn", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 625)
        Tinker 2316
      - AMS of "To R.B. Haydon Esqr on seeing his Picture of Bonaparte in the Island of St. Helena", Rydal Mount, 1831 Aug 1 (Box 16, Folder 626)
        Tinker 2317
      - AMS of "Extempore Effusion, upon reading in the Newcastle Journal, the notice of the death of the Poet, James Hogg", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 627)
        Bound with Tinker 1223, Tinker 2321, and Tinker 2322 Tinker 2318
      - AMS of 6 lines from The Excursion (VII, 976 ff.), 1837 May 15 (Box 16, Folder 628)
        Tinker 2319
      - LS (in Mrs. Wordsworth's hand) to George Crabbe, Jr., n.p., [1834 Feb] (Box 16, Folder 629)
        Tinker 2320
      - ALS to John Hernaman, Rydal Mount, 1835 Nov [30]
        Bound with Tinker 2318 Tinker 2321
      - ALS to John Hernaman, Rydal Mount, 1835 Dec 1
        Bound with Tinker 2318 Tinker 2322
      - ALS to Thomas James Judkin, Rydal Mount, 1836 Oct 20 (Box 16, Folder 630)
        Tinker 2323
      - ALS to Thomas Spring Rice, Rydal Mount, 1839 Sep 6 (Box 16, Folder 631)
        Tinker 2324
      - ALS to John Scott, Rydal Mount, 1816 Apr 18 (Box 16, Folder 632)
        Tinker 2325
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, Rydal Mount, 1840 Sep 25 (Box 16, Folder 633)
        Tinker 2326
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, Rydal Mount, 1843 Oct 4 (Box 16, Folder 634)
        Tinker 2327
    - Young, Edward, 1684-1765
      - ALS to Samuel Richardson, [Welwyn], 1751 Aug 7 (Box 16, Folder 635)
        Tinker 2363
      - ALS to Samuel Richardson, [Welwyn], 1759 Aug 11 (Box 16, Folder 636)
        Tinker 2364
      - AL to Samuel Richardson, [Welwyn], 1760 Sep 8 (Box 16, Folder 637)
        Tinker 2365
- Oversize
  - Byron, George Gordon Byron, Baron, 1788-1824
    - AMS of The Corsair (Canto III, stanza xvii, lines 1690f.), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 638)
    - AMS of Don Juan (Canto IX), 1822 (Box 17, Folder 639)
    - AMS of "Hints from Horace" (lines 657-58 with the accompanying lengthy note), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 640)
  - Eon de Beaumont, Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André Timothée d', 1728-1810
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1763 Nov 10 (Box 17, Folder 641)
  - Morris, William, 1834-1896
    - Illustrations for Cupid and Psyche, in The Earthly Paradise (Box 18, Folder 642)
  - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882
    - "The Duke's Children," autograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 643)
    - "Phineas Redux. Graphic - 1873," autograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 644)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 8, folder 342 (Box 21, Folder 645)